Do you sell cigarettes?
We don't carry them.
I'm sorry.
Out of cigarettes?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Ritual.
It's a ritual.
Oh, back there?
By the tracks?
Yes, I was performing a ritual.
Oh... sorry I intruded then.
What's it for?
It's a secret!
Say, do you know what tomorrow is?
No?
Tomorrow's
my
birthday!
I'm still spiraling.
It's a dark, lonely feeling.
I thought maybe you could rescue me.
Somehow, I still feel that way.
I'm not sure what to do...
But I'm moved by the scent of rain.
Thanks for those smokes.
And...
Happy birthday.
No!
Tomorrow's my birthday.
The simple act of pursuing her
was sufficient.
Having reached an impasse
in my work and in myself,
I sought to acquaint myself
with everyday ennui,
sired by apathy and restlessness.
Ever-fleeing the authenticity
of my own experience,
I was entirely spent by a life,
composed of accumulated fictions.
Um...
are you always alone?
Not today.
Yesterday?
Not really.
Tomorrow?
I'd rather not be.
I'd rather not be alone either.
Say,
do you know today's date?
Monday.
Yesterday?
Sunday.
Tomorrow?
Tuesday.
Did you perform your ritual today?
Yes.
It will make my wish come true.
Your wish?
When my wish comes true,
I can disappear completely.
Disappear, leaving nothing
in the world behind.
That's why I have to keep
performing the ritual.
Until then, the red umbrella protects me.
Say,
what's tomorrow?
Can't you figure it out?
Tomorrow is my birthday.
And so...
I'd rather not be alone.
Um...
What?
Why did you follow me,
that first day?
Why are you following me now?
Well... because you intrigue me.
Same here, then.
This your place?
Yup.
Here?
My unsound heart
and the consuming loneliness
of longing for someone.
Perhaps anyone will do.
As long as that someone
will love me
constantly, ceaselessly,
it will suffice.
"Is this true love?"
"I feel at ease with you."
"We're compatible."
I ponder such ideas everyday.
Sick.
Dad and Mom are sick.
Everybody's sick.
And I'm...
sickest of all.
What's wrong?
Maybe I shouldn't have come.
It's not that.
No one's stood there before...
I mean, it's unusual.
So I felt strange.
Eh?
Do I look strange?
No, not at all.
You look just right.
Like my room?
Probably.
I like it.
Only my favorite things are here.
Including me?
Yup.
You're one of the gang.
I'm okay here.
I like coming back here.
I'm home, mother.
Listen, your sister...
You listening?
She never listened to her mother.
It's too late for regrets now!
Listen to me,
or you'll end up like your sister!
Both of you share that man's blood.
Guess it's hopeless.
I've had it!
Where are you!
Not with that man again.
I won't stand for it!
Will you ever...
Pick up the phone and call me!
All right, all right, I get it.
I worked myself
to the bone to raise you
and now you abandon me.
At least your sister had a heart.
How infuriating!
Listen,
if you keep up this selfish behavior
you'll pay for it.
I swear you will.
You, you, you...
How dare you talk to me that way?!
Your father tortured me,
doing whatever he wanted.
And now my own daughter hates me this much!
What's the point of living...
I'll get out of the hospital tomorrow,
and it's your birthday, too.
Please? Won't you come home?
Sure.
Know what tomorrow is?
Probably, your birthday, right?
That's right!
So let's play together again!
I don't want to be alone
on my birthday.
What are you doing?
Rainy days are days
for my father and sister.
They're both dead.
And tomorrow's my birthday...
No doubt for her,
the truth is only an enemy that wounds her.
The days of her life pass in
loneliness, a darkness without exit.
I longed to ease her sadness
and anxiety, if only a little.
Even if only to atone
for my own past.
Can I be with you?
Sure.
Know what tomorrow is?
Tomorrow's your birthday.
The time is
5:59 AM
and
30 seconds.
The time is
5:59 AM
and
40 seconds.
The time is
5:59 AM
and
50 seconds.
The time is exactly
6 AM.
The time is
6 AM
and 10 seconds.
Good morning!
I'm going to
give you a tour of my house.
First,
this is,
the secret fourth floor!
And this...
This is Lucy.
The secret...
third floor!
And this is...
the secret
second floor!
And this is...
the secret
first floor!
There's a basement.
No!
That's absolutely secret!
You can't go in there!
And this is...
the secret
fifth floor!
And this is
the secret
What?
sixth floor.
And this is
the secret
seventh floor!
Why are they all secret?
Because...
They're our secret.
And finally...
This is
the secret
roof!
These... stairs...
I'm beat.
Getting old...
You like high places?
Not really.
I do.
Sometimes, I come here to check.
Check what?
That I'm still okay.
The sky is pretty.
The stars are pretty.
The moon is pretty.
The light is pretty.
If I don't exist,
everything's pretty.
Maybe it's better if I didn't exist.
How about my blood?
Maybe it's pretty.
Maybe I'll look.
See, I'm still okay.
I didn't let go.
Still okay to be alive.
A blank-faced mosquito falls.
A huge mosquito,
much, much bigger than I.
It slumps and is still.
A much larger creature caught it
and took flight, the mosquito in its grasp.
It flew up and passed right over me.
But it released its grasp
and the mosquito fell.
Still blank.
It drifted down, down, down.
What's that?
The inside of my head.
Such an interesting head.
It's your turn
to talk.
About what?
Something.
Something, huh.
Anything. I want to hear you talk.
You know FireMan?
No.
Well, when I was a kid,
he was like UltraMan.
His enemies attack him
and in the end, he dies.
He ignites.
So he dies.
FireMan ends up burning.
He yells "Fire!" but
actually he's afraid of fire...
Maybe he's FireMan 'cause he burns.
But that wasn't what you wanted.
I don't really get it,
but it's interesting.
That's what she says,
but I wonder...
Actually, all she wanted was
to hear someone's voice.
to stop feeling lonely.
Know what tomorrow is?
Your birthday, right?
Echoes from the
creaking arcade roof opening
and an all too ordinary sky
disturbed my ease.
Can I see you tomorrow?
If I'm still alive.
You like cars?
Not as much as boats and trains,
but well enough.
I like 'em.
Cars.
Why?
Because my big sister did.
Where were you?
I was back at the hotel
getting my things.
That stuff.
No, I mean where
were you 'til now.
I took my usual route here,
the bookstore, department store,
and the toy store today.
No!
I mean where were you
before you came here!
Oh... Tokyo.
Why'd you come?
What? I wanted to think things over.
I was kind of tired.
Tough time?
Well, there was a lot going on.
But really, it was all about nothing.
You're just like my mother.
Mother always said
life is full of tough times.
Must be a wrong number.
No phone calls today?
Yeah, the deal's already done.
What are you doing?
Hm? Nothing...
My usual work exhausts me.
So I'm keeping my distance.
Actually, I wanted to
make live action films, too.
Live action films... films.
Films?
Films...
What's stopping you? You should.
From now on, you're "Director".
I'll call you Director.
Director...
Cut it out.
Cheers.
I want blue, the blue one.
This? This blue?
Ready, go!
Hey, you cheated.
It stopped.
Say, say.
Say,
know what tomorrow is?
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow's your birthday.
You got that right,
Director!
I'm still okay today.
I'm finished.
Yes, yes, I start shooting today,
but there's no telling...
Yes, yeah.
An outline by...
Reel 1.
Rolling.
I'm rolling.
I'm shooting you.
Say something.
She seems to have escaped.
Does my outfit look alright?
Is it okay for the film?
Sure, I think it looks fine.
I don't know much about clothes.
I'm not very knowledge.
It's cute.
Are you shooting...
It's moving.
Happy?
Happy on the train?
Happy on the train with you.
I've never been here.
The unknown.
Yeah, it's exciting.
The streetcar is a perfect means of escape
from the tedium of my days.
The scenery flows by cinematically.
The sound effects are punctual.
My fantasy about her expands.
I won't be bored for some time.
Our idle routine, the days
I spend with her, like a lukewarm bath,
her faint smile seems to agree with me.
Each day, a countdown towards death.
I dare not risk negligence.
All the more reason to film her, I think.
Images, especially animation,
simply embody our
personal and collective fantasies,
manipulating selected information,
and fictional constructs.
Even in live-action film,
recording actuality, does not correspond to reality.
Conversely, reality,
co-opted by fiction, loses its value.
"The inversion of reality and fiction."
None of this matters to me anymore.
My consciousness, my reality,
my subject, all converge in her.
Certainly, she longs to escape into fantasy.
Certainly, I long to escape from fantasy.
I wanted to keep a visual record
of these contradictory phenomena.
But, my behavior is really
no more than an excuse
for my inability to communicate
except through images.
This is the way to the mystery basement.
No trespassing
because the camera is prohibited,
I cannot show you anymore.
My apologies
Outside circumstances
force me to omit the first
through seventh floors.
Next, the roof.
So, this is the roof.
Wow, it's high...
This is where she always checks herself.
You know what tomorrow is?
Yeah, your birthday, right?
Each day, she postpones tomorrow,
by transforming today into yesterday.
A typical day in her life.
She never goes to sleep before dawn,
but she awakens before 6 AM
to dial and listen to the time.
As far as I can tell,
she hardly sleeps at all.
You'll die.
Hey, go to sleep!
Aren't you sleepy?
Don't you want to sleep?
I'm scared to sleep.
When I close my eyes to sleep,
something really heavy
seems to crush my head.
I push it away and away and away,
but it keeps bearing down.
I can't avert my eyes,
so I don't sleep.
I faint.
But I like tomorrow coming!
Because tomorrow...
You know what tomorrow is?
Your birthday, right?
Terrified to face the truth,
she rejects even sleep.
Not that there is actual truth
in the ambiguity of human memory.
Her best and only means
of survival depends on her
destruction and renewal of memory.
Certainly many more days bear
forgetting than joyful commemoration.
What is it that I want from her?
You'd better get some sleep.
You're shooting again tomorrow...
Again, today, I record her image.
Because I find in the act
of capturing her being,
according to my own will,
for my own purpose, relief from my own life.
Images transform my real past into fiction.
Each of us edits and alters our memories.
By giving form and existence
to this process through images,
I reinvent my past, whitewashing it,
into an idealized history.
Re-creating the present as something invulnerable,
as a world of fiction and fantasy.
We are the same, only differing in our methods.
Look what I found.
What's that? Throw it away.
Do you read this stuff?
No, I don't.
I don't!
Liar.
I'm not.
Why not?
Well, I read the softer stuff.
So you do read it. Disgusting.
Like Playboy, or whatever.
"Females drowning in their lust,
coming wherever they please..."
Don't read it!
"Normal sex doesn't do it"
Stop it!
"The nymphomaniacs who lust for kinky settings"
Cut it out. It's embarrassing.
Throw it away.
It's dirty.
You like this stuff too.
What can I say?
It says, "vavoom".
No!
You like it.
No, they're too big.
You do like it.
Do you like sex?
Well, all men like sex.
And you, Director?
Well, the Director
neither likes nor dislikes...
I don't dislike it...
So you do like it.
I don't like it.
'Cause if you do,
you're no more
than male and female.
Just like everybody else.
So I hate it!
I really hate it!
A Kumoha 42 street car.
The type:
20 meters with driver's seat.
Two doors and benches on either side.
Semi-cross seats
perpendicular to the floor.
Street car color:
Grape #2.
Capacity of 104,
68 sitting, 36 standing.
Weight: 45 tons.
Built in 1933.
These two cars are the only ones
of this type still operating in Japan.
Wait a minute.
Hello.
Yeah, in Ube.
Yeah, I'm shooting.
I can't tell whether it's any good or not.
I'll email you an outline when I'm done.
Tell me what you think.
Yeah, sounds good. Sure.
It's from a woman again, Dirty Director!
No, it's not like that.
Lucky you.
At least once a day
you get to talk to someone.
It's not like that.
I don't care who it is.
At least someone calls you.
Want it?
Give it back.
Here.
That night,
her smile disappeared
with the falling rain.
Hey!
You okay?
I'm coming in.
It'll rain tomorrow.
What are you doing?!
Tomorrow's my birthday!
Today is
my father and sister's day!
I like rainy days,
because when it rains,
all the merry people in the world
finally walk with their eyes downcast.
That's why I like rain!
The rain she loves.
What she keeps bottled up on sunny days,
flows as from a broken darn when it rains.
Her feelings of loneliness and sorrow.
These emotions elevate her,
preventing her from
engaging in a certain behavior.
And...
engendering her complex reactions
to the phenomenon called rain.
What is the sadness that she harbors?
No doubt the deaths in her family.
In this moment, I acknowledge yet again,
that in her heart, she yearns
to cease existing.
A brand new morning's here!
A morning of hope!
Open your heart with joy!
Look up at the sky!
Open your vibrant heart
to the song on the radio
and the fragrant breeze!
Now, 1, 2, 3...
I'm okay again today.
Having something to hold onto
when you're scared
is good enough in itself.
And this is my
secret
ritual space.
It always has to be flooded.
It's a really sacred place.
But as of today, it's open.
The Director can come and go.
Videocamera okay!
Not the other one?
This one's cooler.
An umbrella here.
An umbrella.
Don't you need it?
As of today... this.
What's that?
A videocamera.
Matching.
Did you ever have fun?
A hesitant reply isn't a good sign, is it?
Okay then...
A favorite place?
Favorite place...
This sort of place isn't bad...
I loved the desert.
The desert?
Desert.
A simple place with only sand and sky.
Really beautiful.
But it was beautiful
because it was unpopulated.
No humans there to warp it.
A beautiful world
without people.
That sounds lovely.
Like railroad tracks?
What? Yeah.
Why?
Well...
How shall I put it...
Because they are mechanical.
And then rails are fixed, right?
As long as you ride them,
you needn't choose a path.
Perhaps that's a relief.
And you?
I like them.
Why?
Because these two rails
will never come together.
And yet,
the two are one.
That's why!
They left me.
Abused and then abandoned.
I tried everything,
but my fear made me tremble.
The magical powers
of a pair of dice
still sway me
undiminished.
If only one day I could say
I'm so glad I met you.
I hum to myself.
My umbrella!
If I died in your place...
How would the skies part?
How would the wind flow?
Beneath the steps of that dark red space
you used that sharp stick
and struck my bursting...
over and over...
It's no good, I can't write.
Hopeless.
Maybe time to give it up.
What'll I do if I quit?
What do you think I'd...
Oh, sorry, I'll call you back.
Hey, what are you doing?
Today, she didn't
venture near the roof,
or to the railroad tracks.
She never attempted
to leave the room.
Tomorrow's my birthday.
Be happy.
She never discussed what frightened her,
what she wanted to escape.
She no longer saw anyone but herself.
I no longer exist inside of her.
That day passed without us
exchanging a single word,
a single glance,
or lifting the camera to shoot.
For I hadn't the courage
to capture her like this.
Her unrelenting, oppressive reality
began to bear down on me as well.
Unbeknownst to me,
she had found a cat that day.
Look mother,
isn't this cat cute?
It's called Jam.
Look, it's mother, mother.
Our very, very kind mother.
Let's say hello to her, Jam.
You know what tomorrow is?
Tomorrow...
is my birthday.
Her ritual remained interrupted.
Since that day, she hadn't climbed
to the roof, or visited the tracks,
but played with the cat all day.
Playing with the cat seemed to
allow her to avoid herself.
She still slept rarely,
and now barely ate,
only played with the cat.
Nothing else worth
recording took place.
Except that of course we neither
spoke nor exchanged a glance.
I remained locked outside her.
Here, Jam!
Why don't you come?
The cat slipped away that day.
The photographer's dream.
The writer's soul.
The director's obsession.
The actor's disease.
Red cheeks.
Swelling lips.
Tightened strings.
The human heart is fragile
and is easily captured.
An evil song,
drifting through the dark,
envelopes the girl.
You can eat this.
Announcing,
My true mother has arrived.
The girl dances
wildly, wildly
wildly.
She never did come home that day.
And suddenly,
I noticed that I was somewhat
relieved the cat had gone.
Um...
the cat?
Mother.
My mother was inside me.
I've become my mother.
Cut it out!
What are you doing!
Calm down!
Why?! Why weren't you
with me then?!
Why?!
Calm down!
It's your heart.
It's beating away.
A gentle sound...
I've never heard it before...
Don't go anywhere, okay?
Don't disappear like that, okay?
Don't ever leave me alone again, okay?
Promise.
Because tomorrow's my birthday.
Sure... okay.
You have to be
with me on my birthday.
Forever and ever, okay?
What are you thinking?
What?
Oh, sorry.
Seriously?!
Hey, hey, wake up!
Wake up!
It's past 6!
No... hold on...
Don't climb.
Up we go.
Yup.
Okay?
Your heart says I'm okay.
There there...
Which line today?
Amusement park.
I can handle this.
Wait, there's someone scary!
Director! Monkeys!
Monkeys and goats!
I made a huge discovery this morning!
Guess what?
I'm not scared to fall asleep anymore.
Just because you were with me,
I could close my eyes just like that.
And like,
I wasn't scared at all.
Nothing came crashing down.
Actually, my body felt really light.
I could just sleep.
This is amazing!
This is really amazing!
Do you understand what this means?
Amazing discovery!
Really!
Great angle.
The wind's not so bad when I lie like this.
You're right.
Cuddling is nice, isn't it? I like it.
Yeah.
In a way, I like this better
than that.
Liar.
No, really.
Huh, well then,
what do you like about it?
That it's warm.
It's warm...
For me,
when I wake up in the middle of the night,
you're beside me.
Your face is right there.
It's so reassuring.
Amazing, isn't it?
I know what you mean.
But your mouth's
always wide open, and you drool.
You... fool!
Ouch!
Can you make it over?
All these used tires
look like people's ripped off teeth.
Let me shoot too.
Okay? I want to shoot, too.
No, it won't be my film anymore.
Who cares? C'mon.
Let me, let me!
This okay? Is it working?
Give it back.
Say something.
Don't shoot me.
Why are you upset?
I'm not upset.
Liar!
It's true.
Do I look upset?
You do!
I am not upset.
I wonder...
I've been tired lately.
Tired?
Huh, I see.
So what?
Want me to baby you?
Yes, please.
Okay, good boy, good boy.
I'll baby you more.
Will you mother me then?
I want a piggyback.
Piggyback?
Yeah, piggyback.
For real?
A two-shot!
I'm dizzy!
Dizzy.
Know what tomorrow is?
Sure.
That's right!
Tomorrow's my birthday!
Tomorrow's my birthday.
It's nearly a month since I met her.
I'm fed up with the endless "yesterdays",
and lulled by the "todays."
Anxious, too, that tomorrow may bring change,
yet eagerly awaiting the change it may finally bring.
What do I want from this reality I share with her?
The constancy of the past or the change of the future.
However,
these were no more than idle doubts that shifted with my moods.
You snore every night, just like a hedgehog.
These days will come to an end.
Eventually, I'll part with her.
Even my life will end one day.
All the more reason to treasure
these slight, fleeting emotions.
But the excess of boredom and intimacy
were simply exhausting me.
And I realized that gradually,
the times that being with her depressed me,
outstripped the times that I enjoyed it.
Someday that'll happen to me.
You know, today,
there was this blue car
in front of the shrine,
and this car, you know,
was really cute...
Hey, you listening?
You paying attention?
I've gotten really good.
Oh, it stopped.
I'm off to the store.
He hates me?
Does he?
He hates me.
Hates me, hates me, hates me!
I'll be left alone again.
They left me.
Abused and then abandoned.
I tried everything
but my fear made me tremble.
The magical powers of a pair of dice...
...still sway me.
If only one day I could say,
"I'm so glad I met you."
I hum to myself.
Listen, your sister...
You listening?
She never listened to her mother.
It's too late for regrets now!
Listen to me, or you'll
end up like your sister!
Both of you share
that man's blood.
Guess it's hopeless.
I've had it! Where are you?!
Not with that man again!
I won't stand for it!
Shut up, clueless!
You're so patronizing!
All you ever want is
for me to be grateful!
Always, always, always.
You're just patronizing me!
You don't even have a clue
what it is I really want! Not a clue!
How dare you!
You only remember what you gave me,
but not how you mistreated me!
Right?
Or what, we're even for all your troubles?
Go ahead and die!
I won't care!
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
Why were you nice to me then?
Mother...
Why don't you answer?
Her heart is overcome by a world
awash in cruelty, harshness,
hatred and loneliness.
But that is the way of the world.
Each of us fears its absurdity, and curses it.
And yet, the world is immeasurably vast,
and gentleness, mercy and
empathy linger in our hearts.
I desperately wanted her
to know this reality as well.
Hello...
Hey, there.
What's wrong?
But her heart is so delicate and vulnerable.
Am I really capable of embracing
the endless darkness inside it?
Perhaps I'm incapable of accepting her...
I find myself enveloped
in an anxiety I cannot shake.
Today, again, I can do nothing.
6 in the morning,
she's back to her usual self
She's returned to her little world
constructed entirely
of her protections, denying the existence
of whatever can harm her.
Except now she has chosen to rely on me.
Yeah, it always sounds good.
She begins another day of life,
brimming with fantasy,
plastered in self-deception,
sealed by oblivion.
My own faint panic,
"I've got to do something"
is futilely idle.
What are you doing?
Nothing, just working.
Let's go outside then.
Shoot your movie,
that's your job, right?
Is that work?
It's your job.
In Japan today, all forms of expression,
beginning with images, serve only
as either
time-killing entertainment
for those without occupation,
or as momentary respite
for those who are afraid of pain.
People desire either real scandals
amplified by rawness,
or,
the illusion of beautifully adapted fictions.
It is true of me.
Unable to create appropriate relationships,
I escape into a fictional world,
constructed on a fantasy of daily life.
Even this film, when completed,
will become a device to deliver
a certain amount of pleasure.
Devoid of surprises,
and a measure of time spent in peace.
Who wants images beyond that?
Who needs them?
By then, I had abandoned
her as a visual construct.
I didn't want to film anything.
As long as she was present,
I didn't need to make a film.
I had always been entranced with the idea of
being madly loved, and loving madly.
And yet this was a stupendous burden, exhausting.
Could I really bear it?
Long time...
So you came back!
Hey, wait!
Hey! Hey!
Wait, dammit!
What's that about?
I gotta go.
Hey, don't bother.
I said wait! Hey!
Hey!
Give it back,
I know you've got it.
Hey! You do, right!
No, I'm not my sister!
You're crazy!
Excuse
You okay?
Hello.
Sorry about that...
A reunion? Right now?
A toast to his triumphant return!
You forgot, right?
Oh... Sorry, sorry.
Where were you?!
And you?
Where were you?
With some woman?
No, what are you saying?
I was out drinking
with my old friends.
Liar, liar.
It's the truth.
Liar.
And where were you?
Liar!
I'm not lying. It's the truth.
There's nothing left.
Nothing but your heartbeat.
Ever kissed someone?
I have.
Maybe I haven't ever.
Have you ever killed someone?
No...
Maybe.
In my head.
Me too.
You want to have sex?
If I have sex with you,
will you stay forever?
You actually like it, right?
Much better than cuddling.
You just put up with that, right?
You want to see
and touch my breasts, right?
Then, have sex with me.
But don't go anywhere.
Don't abandon me.
I'll do whatever you ask.
Don't hate me.
Don't start hating me.
Ouch.
No, no!
If I do this,
I will become my sister...
I'll become my sister!
I'm... Still...
If I died in your place.
How would the skies part.
How would the wind flow.
Beneath the steps of that dark red space
you used that sharpened stick
over and over
striking my
quivering lips
swollen to bursting
tasting
of sorrow and betrayal.
That song
has left me.
I peer back again and again
at that dreamlike state.
Oh, hello.
Sorry, I'll call you back later.
Hello.
How unusual. Calling at this hour.
Cat got your tongue?
Hello, hello...
What are you...
Come to bed.
You read this?
Why...
What'd you think?
Why?
It's your movie.
Because you have to?
Are you with me because
you have to be for work?
No, that's not what I meant.
Just like my father?
Just like my sister?
Just like my mother?
It doesn't matter if you don't like it.
Am I worthless?
Do you hate me?
Are you going away?
Tell me you won't.
That woman on the phone...
You were just tempted when
she called you, right?
What woman?
She's nobody...
Irrelevant...
I can't hear you.
I can't hear your heartbeat.
There's one answer.
Two answers.
Three answers.
How many answers?
What makes you like this...
By 6 that morning, she had disappeared.
Are you a friend of my sister's?
You dating her?
Well, something like that.
Huh... That girl got a boyfriend...
Oh, sorry.
I never thought she'd do it.
Her sister appeared instead.
Finally, she'd rejected even herself.
It's none of my business,
but be nice to her, okay?
Come to think of it,
she always liked this kind of place.
I feel sorry for her.
Our parents split up
when she was young,
Father walked out on both of us.
Wound up dead with the new woman.
Did it rain on that day?
No, went ablaze.
A fire?
Yes, on her birthday.
And, your mother?
A streetcar hit her.
On her birthday, she'd always cry,
"Why did they leave me?"
Our mother was a terrible person.
She blamed anything bad on someone else.
It was Dad's fault,
that woman's fault,
my sister's fault, my fault,
the world's fault.
It never occurred to her
the fault might be hers.
My poor sister.
She was always compared to me.
She only heard nagging,
"Why can't you be like your sister?"
It was like she was no good.
She must have suffered.
I wonder how she'll
ever learn to like herself.
There's someone I'd like to see. You coming?
None of your business, butt out.
You...
New guy, huh...
Must run in the family.
Listen, cut the crap.
You only show up when it suits you.
What's with that face?
Same as last time?
Seen my cat?
Listen, you...
My cat, my cat,
you know, Jam.
No I don't.
How the hell would I know?
Liar, liar, liar, liar...
You deny attacking my little sister, too?
What are you talking about?
You are her, not her sister.
No I'm not.
Your sister went away a long time ago.
You ranted about killing her.
I say I'm not.
You were babbling some crap
about how you killed her.
No...
You do this to me all the time.
You ask me to let you stay
'cause you got nowhere else,
then you split.
Now it's about some cat!
You come wandering back
ranting about a cat!
Don't mess with me!
Say something!
Goddammit!
After all I did for you!
You don't get it, do you!
What an idiot!
Don't ever go again.
What the...
I'm...
Oh, great. Great!
Being with you makes me crazy.
Drives me nuts!
You're crazy.
Both of you are demented!
Wanna be like your sister?
Well you already are.
Sleep around, get knocked up,
spitting image of that sister you love!
Huh!
I'm sick of you both.
No...
Crazy, right?
Hey,
you pulling the same,
"Go away" crap on him?
Sister!
Sister! Sister!
Your sister used to say...
"My own sister scares me."
Don't!
Why does it always have to be
so damn dramatic?
Forget it. Give me back the ring, the ring.
Don't touch me!
What?!
How dare you
"All I did for you" me!?
You never did a thing yourself!
My sister did everything!
Who do you think you are!
I've had it with you!
Stop...
Spit it out! You!
Please stop.
Give back the ring!
Who you callin' stupid?!
Who doesn't get it?!
Calm down.
Let go!
I've had it!
Go away!
Get out of my life!
Give me a break.
Sister, why were
you with that guy?
That guy...
After you disappeared,
he came after me.
Why did you have to go away?
But it's too bad.
You pretended to like me,
but you didn't.
So God punished you.
Be happy.
Hello.
You had a phone call.
Who?
It was... your mother.
No...
She's still alive.
I need to kill her.
It's not true,
'cause she's dead.
It's not a lie.
She's coming to see you tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
What for?
Don't know...
Maybe she's worried about you.
After all that?
After all...
She calls you all the time.
Why'd you answer my phone?
Keep out of my business!
I'm sorry,
but it's what's best for you.
Liar!
I'm not lying.
Go away!
You go away, too!
Don't run away!
I'm not running!
You run away from everything
you don't like, and wind up
in your own little world.
Not true!
You just deny anything you don't like.
That's why you want everyone to go away!
Shut up!
Cut the crap! You depress me!
Why are you still here?
I told you to go...
Because I...
want to be with you.
I...
like...
you...
Lies!
It's true.
I like you.
You're lying just like everybody else.
Liar!
I like you.
Why are you so nice to me?
I wonder...
Let's go home.
When I was little, my mother cursed my father
to drive him away.
Mother's curse came to pass
and my father left.
I tried hard
to keep her from driving me away.
But she told me,
even though she never told my sister.
It was my birthday.
A red umbrella and red shoes.
My mother bought them for me
when we went shopping together.
The first things that weren't
my sisters hand-me-downs.
They matched my mother's.
But my mother threw them away.
She called them old.
Said she didn't need them.
When I saw that,
I thought she'd do that to me one day.
I'm scared of being alone.
But I'm scared of mother, too.
So I cursed everyone to drive them away.
The curse will come to pass on my birthday.
So my birthday always has to be tomorrow.
But mother didn't go away.
So I had to kill her
in my head, over and over.
But suddenly,
I realized that I had to leave.
So I began dressing up.
Tomorrow
would bring my
new and happy life.
But I don't know
what to do about tomorrow.
You never know about tomorrow.
All we really know
is that tomorrow we'll still be together.
What do you say?
Want to try to see your mother?
You've been okay?
Leave me alone.
I can't leave you alone.
But you did.
Your own mother? Leaving you alone?
For a long time.
I left you alone for a long time?
When did I leave you alone?
When did your mother leave you alone?
Ever since I was little,
you always left me alone...
You only cared for my sister.
Excuse me.
Did her sister pass away?
Is she still alive?
We are apart, but...
She worries about you, too.
She called me the other day.
We'd been out of touch.
I'm sorry, it's not that.
I left you alone.
I was so busy thinking...
about myself, that maybe
I didn't think about your feelings.
Maybe I was difficult for a long time.
Maybe I was no good.
Always complaining, always getting angry.
Maybe I never did anything for you.
Maybe I only...
thought about myself.
Maybe I couldn't really love you.
Now...
What?
I really want you to come home.
I know it's selfish...
I'm lonely.
I know that's selfish of me.
What about when I was lonely?
What about all those
years when I was alone?!
All those...
You couldn't have cared less
when I needed your love,
but now you're lonely,
you come to get me!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
What! After all this time,
now you're lonely!
Is that what it is?
That's how it is...
That's how...
When I was lonely,
you just ignored me...
Now you...
Go away!
I'm asking you, go away!
Just go... Just go...
Just go away, now!
I'm sorry.
No!
I'm sorry, sorry, sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'll be waiting.
Just once, won't you come home?
Won't you come home just once? Please.
I know...
Please come home...
I'm sorry.
Mother!
Wake up from your dream?
Or is this part of your dream?
Are we still dreaming a dream?
But this is our reality...
Your reality.
Your birthday
will come, on the day
you were born.
Smile,
please smile.
Thank you.
What day
is that?
December 7th.
My birthday.
The red hair I got from my mom
Braided in two
Swaying in the wind
Why, why, I still don't know
Calmly I stood up
Scissors in hand
and cut off those braids
It was a sunny day
The future had no meaning
I was helpless, had no words
But the scent of the way home
It was tender
I can live
Somebody was laughing
It was a very sunny day
With no more hair
I cut off my arms
kept cutting until I could
It felt warm
Dancing, with my bloody arms
Without you
there was nothing here
but only the bright sun
It was a very sunny day
Couldn't even cry
The land had no limit
Beauty surrounded me
I was singing
in a white dress
The line of people far away
I could've cried with a rain like today
It was a sunny day
The future had no meaning
I was helpless, had no words
But the scent of the way home
It was tender
I can live
Somebody was laughing
It was a very sunny day